Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...Goodbye.
Kobato.
What are you grinning at?
Huh? I was grinning?
Yeah, with the happiest, most satisfied look on your face.
Were you having a really good dream or something?
Yes! A long time ago...
Hmm?
Um...
It was a really happy dream but...
Was it a dream about the place you want to go to?
Sign: Closing Notice
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
What are we cleaning today?
Excuse me.
Good work, see you!
I'm sorry there are so many to tie up.
Don't worry about it! I'll just work even harder!
Thank you. To make something new, old things need to be thrown out.
Need to be thrown out, huh?
Let's start carrying out the ones that are ready to go.
Okay!
When we're finished with this, why don't we have some tea?
Without Fujimoto here, this is rather difficult, isn't it?
Fujimoto's really busy with his work, isn't he?
Thank you.
You don't need to force yourself to work if you don't have time for it.
No, please let me work.
There's no need for you to save up money anymore, is there?
If you're firing me, please just say so.
No, that's not it at all!
You just don't get it...
I'm sorry...
for deciding to close down the Nursery.
But there's something I want you to know.
Right now, I'm happy with this.
I don't regret it at all.
And I'm not doing this because Okiura told me to.
The one to make the final decision was me.
That's how I feel about things.
I see.
What?
I was wondering if you would be willing to come to the Nursery just one more time?
Um, some of your belongings are still—
They aren't.
And even if they were, you can just toss them all.
But...
I'm busy, I don't have time to go.
This is Fujimoto.
I apologize, but I'm going to be an hour late today.
Sign: Closing Notice
Fujimoto?
Get outta the way!
Huh?
I thought you were going to be late today?
I finished early.
Why are you looking so worried?
You're even making me depressed!
I'm sorry.
What are you thinking about?
What do you want to do?
I don't know, but...
But?
It hurts here.
According to Miss Sayaka, Yomogi Nursery closing is a good thing...
And yet...
Is this about Fujimoto?
Huh? What about Fujimoto?
What kind of reaction is that?!
Are you not conscious of your own feelings at all?
Man... honestly.
Kiyokazu?
Good morning.
Do you have work today too?
Yes.
But today's the day they're tearing down the Nursery—
Goodbye.
You should've taken off today...
Well, he's gone now. I think I'm going to go out for a bit too.
Go out?
Yeah. I'll be back by tonight though.
Don't make that face!
Yes...
You hurry up too. You're going to be late.
Right!
Keep going, keep going, keep going...
Stop!
Thanks.
Teach, you have any luggage left?
I took everything out already yesterday.
Well, then I guess it's okay to turn it over to the workers.
Where's that guy who's always glaring?
At work.
What? No sense of courtesy, that one.
We're helping you guys out too. What a cold guy.
He is not!
Fujimoto's busy.
My bad.
Mr. Okiura just asked me to take care of all of this by nightfall.
He said that he wouldn't be able to come by for a while.
Yes, I've heard.
It seems like there's a lot of stuff going on above us too.
We grunts wouldn't understand though, I guess.
T-Then Mr. Okiura is...
Don't worry about it! He'll be just fine.
He's Mr. Okiura after all!
Miss Sayaka!
Kobato!
You're all here!
What's the matter?
Well, cause today's goodbye, you see...
We came to see you guys!
I made sure to tell my mommy first!
I see. Thank you.
Boss! Can we start?
Teach, is it all right?
Please.
Come, it's dangerous. Let's all step back, okay?
Okay.
Yeah! Go ahead!
Bye bye...
I'll say it one more time.
That's impossible.
Give it up.
Master Genko! That's so mean! Starting without me...
Thanks for the food!
Zuisho! Be quiet.
Right... huh?
What did you say? Catch Ushagi?!
Yeah. Take Ushagi as a hostage, and use her as leverage against him.
Do you really think god is going to go along with that sort of deal?
It's better than doing nothing, isn't it?
Taking into account our current situation, that's not a light contact you're dealing with.
It's as Ginsei says. He's looking at this a lot more candidly than you are.
We can deal with how light or serious it is afterwards!
Just stop!
Didn't you learn anything from what happened last time?
No, you two, stop!
Do you plan on trying to force your way through again?
Who's the one who's going to get hurt?
If you don't know, I'll tell you!
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
What god wanted you to learn might've been patience.
Well, that's definitely my weak point.
Hey!
I got it! I won't do anything.
I am Iorogi.
I will be with you from now on.
Teach! After the clean up's done, entrance will be prohibited.
I understand. Thank you.
You guys too, good luck.
See ya.
I imagined it was only about that big...
but when you look at it like this, it's different, isn't it?
Kobato, I have a favor to ask of you... is that all right?
Yes.
Become Fujimoto's strength for him, won't you?
I think Yomogi Nursery might've actually been holding him down.
Holding him down to what?
To believing he needs to constantly struggle and overachieve.
I should've noticed that about him sooner, but I also ended up relying on him.
Thanks so much, Fujimoto!
Mr. Kiyokazu!
Fold origami?
I should've told him to follow his own dreams and do what he wanted to do.
But!
Fujimoto really worked so hard...
Yes. That's why it was too much.
Because Fujimoto worked too hard.
That's why you'll have to take care of him, okay, Kobato?
Stay with him.
You would be better...
That's not my place.
That's no longer my place.
Kobato!
Hello, I'm back.
Something terrible has happened!
Domoto.
You...
I didn't contact anyone from Yomogi Nursery, just as I promised.
I did tell your landlady though.
Sorry, Kobato.
He said he didn't want to worry you.
That's just his way of caring for—
Um... your arm...
I-I'm glad that your injuries weren't serious!
But don't push yourself too hard though, okay?
Everyone will worry.
I'm sure it's inconvenient not being to use one hand.
If there's anything I could do, please let me know!
When I first met you at Yomogi Nursery...
I guess I should've told you.
If you're doing this out of sympathy or curiosity, stop it.
If you're pitying me, please stop.
I'm not!
It's annoying!
It's not that... Fujimoto...
You're wrong...
Is that... for me?
It's telling you that you have until the next full moon to gather the rest of the konpeito.
And if you don't, your fate will be sealed, as according to your contract.
Hey, Ushagi.
How do we extend the deadline?
What's going to happen now?
What do you think he should do?
I wonder.
It's really up to him.
He definitely feels a responsibility for things at least.
If that battle hadn't happened, that girl wouldn't have...
...wouldn't have been dragged in, and would've been able to live her life without that happening?
If there's anything I can do, I'll do it!
So please, until all four seasons turn once again...
No, even just one more season is fine!
I'm on my knees!
Is that a no?
Hey!
Your smile falls in that space
between the things I've lost and the things I've gained.
It seems as if I could reach it, but I can't.
It's not as if I can fly...
Even though I only wanted to make you smile...
What purpose do they serve, these useless wings of mine?
All I can do is smile by your side.
I wonder if it's okay to only warm your heart
when, at the very least, I want to envelop you in warmth.
Have you noticed? I want to embrace you with my wings.
And now, I am able to smile.
Next
...Kobato's Wish.